原创翻译  双语字幕
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
这里有完满的生活
There's a whole life going on here
而你并不是其中一份子
that you're not even a part of.
首席翻译官
█ 网易见外
你以为我不知道自己错过了什么
You think I don't know what I've missed?
我说的不只是生日  哈维
I'm not just talking about birthdays, Harvey.
-我旧病复发了  -什么
- I got sick again. - What?
首席校对官
人人译视界
·
人人
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
-你知不知道  -知道什么
- Did you know? - Know what?
盖文·安德鲁本来要找我给他洗钱
That Gavin Andrews was gonna ask me to launder money for him?
翻译     小僵僵 辰星晓Reginamoon 木浅 rotar 克里斯托啊托
帮我脱身
Help me get out of this.
求你了萨曼莎
Please, Samantha.
我本该听你的话  但我还有家人
I should have listened to you, but I have a family.
我想跟你要个完美的孩子
I want to make a perfect baby with you.
翻译     Giggles silverlining 不見曦月 黑锤斯特 海云生 暴走小罐头
-你确定吗  -确定
- Are you sure? - Absolutely.
我不想只是停止预防措施
And I don't want to just be pulling the goalie.
校对     木浅
我想努力尝试  我想现在就开始尝试
I want to start trying, and I want to start trying right now.
我知道你认为我们是在竞争同一件事
I know you think we're in competition for the same thing,
时间轴     张小满   姜姜
但不是的
but we're not.
罗伯特·赞恩对我做出了承诺
Robert Zane made me a promise:
下一个上墙的名字一定是我的
the next name that goes up on the wall is mine.
后期     斯人
为什么要告诉我
Why are you telling me this?
因为如果你总觉得我是为了超过你
Because we're never gonna trust each other
我们是无法信任对方的
if you think I'm trying to get ahead of you.
总监     木浅
我没有  因为我已经在你前面了
I'm not, because I already am.
┌
┐
└
┘
人人影视官方客户端
唯一下载渠道
app.YYeTs.com
┌
┐
└
┘
希拉
Sheila.
已经九点多了  你要迟到了
It's after 9:00. You're gonna be late.
迟就迟吧  因为我有事要问你
Then I'll be late, because there's something i need to ask you.
问吧  想问什么都可以
Yeah, of course. You can ask me anything.
路易  你以前有让别的女人怀上过吗
Louis, have you ever gotten a woman pregnant before?
好吧...
Okay, uh...
这是哪一出
Where is this going?
我之所以这么问  是因为你还没有
I'm asking because you haven't gotten
让这个女人怀上
this woman pregnant yet either.
希拉  我们才开始尝试
Sheila, we just started trying,
而且我觉得我所做的
and I think what I've been doing
已经超出标准要求了
is more than meeting the standards.
路易  你是个A或A+爱人  众所周知
Louis, you are an A/A-plus lover. Everyone knows that.
-还有个"或"吗  -那不是重点
- There's a slash? - That's not the point.
重点是  你有没有考虑过一种可能性
The point is, have you ever considered the possibility
你发的是空枪
that you're shooting blanks?
考虑这个的次数不比我考虑
No more than I would consider
自己是否有脸面来得多
the possibility that I don't have a face.
我明白  路易
I get that, Louis,
你的精液八成是品质优良的
and you probably have the sperm of a thoroughbred,
但我希望你能去做个检查
but I'd like you to get yourself checked.
希拉  如果我没理解错你的意思的话
Sheila, if you're asking what I think you are,
我可不想去一个大家...
I don't want to go to a place where people do...
干那事的地方
that...
除非绝对有这个必要
unless it's absolutely necessary.
这我也明白  但事实是
I get that, too, but the fact is,
我已经不年轻了  我们没时间挥霍了
I'm not getting any younger and we don't have time to waste,
所以我正在做检查
so I'm getting myself checked,
我希望你也一样去做
and I'm asking you to do the same.
这个是地址
So here's the address.
你预约了今天
You have an appointment today.
没问题  希拉  我会去的
Okay, Sheila, I'll get it done.
谢谢
Thank you.
哈维  有时间吗
Harvey, do you have a second?
当然  路易  什么事
Sure, Louis, what is it?
你有去检查过你的精液吗
Did you ever have to test your sperm?
-什么  -希拉想让我去检查一下
- What? - Sheila wants me to,
但我觉得我没办法在那些地方做
but I don't think I can do it in one of those places.
路易  我不想谈这个话题
Louis, I don't want to have this conversation.
我们的牙医是同一个人已经够糟的了
It's bad enough that we share the same dentist.
哈维  拜托了
Harvey, come on.
我们正在努力造人
We're trying to have a baby,
我也找不到第二个人说这事了
and I don't have anyone else to talk to about this.
好吧  你...你有什么问题
Okay, what-- what's your problem?
问题就是我从在被迫的情况下试过
Problem is, I've never had to do it under duress before.
我不知道要怎么做
I don't know how.
你何不学学其他人
Well, why don't you do it like everyone else does?
-用照片  -我不用照片
- Use pictures. - I don't use pictures.
我只会想着希拉
I only think of Sheila,
但身边有一堆陌生人的话我做不到
and I can't do that with a bunch of strangers there.
那要是希拉在你面前呢
Well, what did you do before Sheila?
我不想谈这个
I don't wanna talk about it.
我不想谈的不光这一点
Well, I don't want to talk about any of this.
哈维  拜托
Harvey, come on.
好吧  所以现在情况是这样
All right, look...
你不能用图片
you can't use pictures;
你也不愿意幻想希拉
you don't want to think about Sheila.
但你必须得想点什么
Well, then, you'll have to think of something
除了希拉以外能挑起你性致的东西
that turns you on that isn't Sheila.
你是说让我想一个没有生命的物体
You mean think about an inanimate object.
没错  路易  我就是这个意思
Yes, Louis, that's what I mean.
-你原来这么做过吗  -当然了
- Have you done that before? - Of course I have.
-你用的是什么  -我才不要告诉你
- What do you use? - No, I'm not telling you that.
哈维  拜托
Harvey, please.
好吧  你要听真话
All right. You want the truth?
一般情况下
Sometimes...
我想的是
I think about...
番茄
tomatoes.
-真的假的  -如果你仔细想想的话
- Really? - Well, if you think about it,
它们是最性感的水果
they're the most sensual fruit.
番茄不是蔬菜吗
I thought they were a vegetable?
我都跟你掏心掏肺了  你还在意细节
I am opening my soul to you here; don't criticize me.
抱歉  你说的对
I'm sorry, you're right.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
祝你好运  哥们儿
Good luck in there, buddy.
没错  番茄  该死的
Yeah. Tomatoes, holy shit.
真是想不到
Never thought of that.
你想告诉我这是什么情况吗
You wanna tell me what that was all about?
不想  我猜我们的谈话内容
No, because I'm guessing you listened to
你全都听见了
the entire conversation,
不用我再来解释一遍
which means you know what it's about.
既然这样的话
In that case,
我最想知道的是  番茄那个是真的吗
what I really want to know is: is it true about the tomatoes?
你我都清楚那是假的
I think we both know it's not.
就跟我们都知道正确答案是
Just like we both know it's really
草莓和鲜奶油
strawberries and whipped cream.
-怎么  现在说这些太早了  -不是
- What, too soon? - No.
但这里是办公室  其他人可不是聋子
But this is an office, and someone could overhear
他们听到就会误以为现在是十三年前
and misunderstand that that was 13 years ago.
是吗  我觉得像是十二年半之前
Really? 'Cause it feels like 12 and 1/2 to me.
-你是个傻子  -不  路易才是傻子
- You're an idiot. - No, Louis is an idiot.
因为他真信了我想的是番茄那些鬼话
because he believed I think about tomatoes.
但是如果希拉真的想要他去检查精子
And if Sheila wants him to get his swimmers checked,
我们不能嘲笑他必须对着杯子
we shouldn't mock that he has to do that...
做那些事
in a cup...
-脑子里想的还是番茄  -你说的对
- thinking about tomatoes. - You're absolutely right.
我们是应该严肃一点
We should take it very seriously.
番茄真的一点也不好笑
Tomatoes.
你知道吗
Okay, you know what?
虽然我也很想一整天都在这里开玩笑
As much as I would love to do this all day,
但我过来是想告诉你
I came in here to tell you
你需要给马库斯打个电话
you need to call Marcus.
马库斯  关于什么事
Marcus? About what?
我不清楚  但他给我留了言
I don't know, but he left me a message
-让你打给他  -如果他想让我打给他
- that he wants you to call him. - Well, if he wants me to call,
为什么要给你留言
why would he be leaving a message for you?
因为每次马库斯真的需要你的时候
Because when Marcus really needs you,
他找的都是我
he calls me.
这种情况只发生过两次
He's only ever done that twice,
所以不管他需要什么  肯定很重要
which means whatever it is he needs, it's important.
好吧  唐娜  我会打给他的
All right, Donna, I'll call him.
今天就打  哈维
Today, Harvey.
一定要今天就打
Today.
嘿  哈维
Hey, Harvey.
很高兴你打过来了
I'm glad you called.
唐娜应该转告给你我的留言了吧
I take it Donna gave you my message?
她是这么做了  发生了什么事
She did. What's going on?
-我要离婚了  -你说什么
- I'm getting a divorce. - What?
我明白这很难理解
I know.
我也知道下面这些话不好开口
And I know it is a big ask,
但我希望你能做我的律师
but I was hoping that you could represent me.
马库斯  等等  到底发生了什么
Marcus, hold on. When did this happen?
上次见面的时候一切还好好的
The last time I was up there everything seemed fine.
但现在一切都不好了  虽然我也不想
Yeah, well, it's not fine, and as much as I hate it,
但这就是她要的结果
this is what she wants.
你要想让我帮你
If you want me to help you,
光一句离婚可不行  我要更多信息
I'm gonna need to know more than that.
你想知道什么  哈维
What do you want me to tell you, Harvey?
我们渐行渐远了
That we grew apart?
-是的  -别跟我扯  我了解你
- Well, we did. - Bullshit, I know you.
-你有话没告诉我  -确实
- It's not the full story. - You're right, it's not,
你过来之后我就把一切都告诉你
and I will tell you everything when you get up here.
我可没说要过去
I didn't say I was coming up there,
除非你现在告诉我发生了什么
and I'm not going to unless you tell me what's going on, right now.
我出轨了  行了吧
I slept with someone, all right?
-什么  -我犯浑了
- You did what? - I was stupid,
出轨了
and I had an affair,
我知道你现在很生气
and I know you want to rip my head off right now--
说的没错  非常生气
You're damn right, I do!
你比任何人都清楚婚外情对家庭的伤害
'Cause you know better than anyone what that does to a family.
但现在我不在乎这些
Right now, I don't care.
你说什么你再给我说一遍
What the hell did you just say to me?
哈维  你一直说
Harvey, you're always telling your clients
你不掺和客户的私事
that your issues are your issues
也不对他们评头论足
and that you don't judge people for what they do.
所以现在我不想听你教训我
So right now I don't need to hear how I screwed up.
我只想知道你准备我帮我
What I need to hear is that you're on your way up here
解决这事并保住孩子
to help make sure that I don't lose my kids.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
抚养权之战  哈维
I'm talking about custody, Harvey,
因为凯蒂雇了一位厉害的离婚律师
because Katie hired a shark to represent her.
意味着如果你不想结束地很难堪
Which means even if you didn't want this to turn into a fight...
我不能冒险
I can't risk not treating it like one,
而我知道避免灾难的最好方法
and the best way I know to avoid a fight
就是带一个重磅炸弹过去
is to show up with a howitzer--
哈维
and, Harvey...
你是我最大的杀手锏
the biggest howitzer I know is you.
好吧  马库斯  我过去
All right, Marcus, I'll come up.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
诉讼双雄
第八季  第五集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
你泡好茶了
All right, you have your tea.
现在去图书馆吧
Now let's get you set up in the library.
那个我从这都能看见满是书的房间吗
You mean the room with the books I can literally see from here?
乔伊  别耍脾气
Joy, I don't need to have any attitude.
我自己能搞定  爸  谢了
I can set myself up, Dad, thanks.
新律师越来越年轻气盛了  是不是
These associates get younger and angrier, don't they?
那不是新律师  是我女儿
That's not an associate; that's my daughter.
你以为我不知道吗
And you think i didn't know that?
一英里外就闻到了九年级叛逆女孩的味道
I can spot a ninth-grade pushback from a mile away.
我问你  你怎么管孩子
Let me ask you something: how'd you manage your kids?
什么叫做管孩子
What do you mean, manage 'em?
乔伊在学校惹麻烦了  所以来这里
I mean, Joy got in trouble at school, that's why she's here.
虽然她很麻烦
And she may be a pain in the ass,
但她完成作业速度飞快
but she finishes her homework in 18 seconds
而且今天我只有文书工作
and all I have today is paperwork.
我懂了
I got it.
你女儿不听话
Your daughter won't listen
你也不想和她说话
and you don't want to talk to her, anyway.
不  我只是不知道
No, I just don't know
说什么她才会听
what to say to her to get her to hear me.
那是因为有时候
That's because sometimes
无法让他们听你的话
there is no way to get them to hear you.
但也许他们能听进去别人的话
But they might hear someone else.
一个更酷的人
Someone--someone cool.
-比如你吗  -不  不
- Someone like you? - No, no, no.
-不是我  -拜托  格雷琴
- Not me. - Come on, Gretchen,
-怎样你才愿意  -我不是说我不愿意
- what's it gonna take? - I'm not saying I won't do it.
-而是这不管用  -为什么
- I'm saying it won't work. - Why not?
因为不能选你觉得酷的人
Because it can't be someone you think is cool...
而是她觉得酷的人
It has to be someone she thinks is cool.
瞧瞧这悟性
Well, look at that.
也许你还有得救
Maybe you're not doomed after all.
现在给我让开
Now, move out of the way.
我要倒点杏仁牛奶喝
I gotta get me some of that almond milk.
生育诊所
你好
Hello.
我是路易·利特  我是来
My name is Louis Litt, I'm here to, uh...
你懂的  撸一管
You know, make a deposit.
没问题
Ah, of course.
11点  你来得真准时
11:00, right on the dot.
守时能让我大脑清醒
Well, punctuality helps me get in the right head space.
那不如你先看看我们的预备材料...
Then why don't you take a look at our preparatory materials--
你开口提问前  我保证不管你需要什么
and before you ask, I promise, whatever you need,
-我们都应有尽有  -那太棒了
- we've got you covered. - Oh, that's great.
那我要浏览一下
Then I'll just take a quick look
-《华尔街日报》  -华什么
- at "The Wall Street Journal." - The what?
《华尔街日报》  美国新闻纪实报纸
"The Wall Street Journal." America's paper of record.
你要《华尔街日报》做什么
What do you need "The Wall Street Journal" For?
什么意思  我要它做什么
What do you mean, what do I need it for?
我用它来办事
I need it to conduct my business.
但我们这里不能办事
But we don't conduct business here.
不  不是那种事
No, not that kind of business.
-而是这种事  -你是说...
- This kind of business. - Are you telling me...
对  我需要一份《华尔街日报》
Yes. I need a "Wall Street Journal,"
《福布斯》和《投资者周刊》
a "Forbes," "Investor's Weekly"--
任何财政信托类型的读物
anything of a fiscal and fiduciary nature.
我们没有这些东西
Well, we don't have those things.
你是谁  你刚才还说我需要任何东西
Who are you? You just said anything I need
你们都应有尽有  你怎么回事
you got me covered. What is your problem?
这不是诊所的  但是...
Well, it's not the clinic's, but...
报纸上有房地产版块
I have the real estate section of the newspaper.
给我看看
Give me that shit.
标准  标准  什么什么的
Standard, standard, standard, blah, blah, blah...
我靠  他们对一个两室房要价...
Holy shit, they want how much for a two bedroom--
太性感了  这有用
Mm, Chubby Checker. That'll work.
-真的吗  -没错  真的
- Really? - Yes, really.
我需要一个房间  现在就要
I need a room. I need one now.
跟别人一起都可以
I'll even share it with somebody.
-快啊  给我杯子  -好吧
- Come on, get the cup. - All right...
-拿杯子  -这边
- Get the cup! - This way.
萨曼莎  你有空吗
Samantha, you got a second?
我只剩不到四小时
What I have is less than four hours
要找到音赛特药物公司剥夺我们客户
to find proof Insight Drugs has ripped off
-心脏药物治疗的证据  -太糟糕了
- our client's heart medication. - That's too bad,
因为我有事需要帮忙
because I need help with something,
而你是最佳人选
and you're the perfect person.
-你要找我帮忙  -没错
- You're asking for my help? - Yes, I am.
-什么事  -两个威廉姆斯的对决
- What's the case? - Williams versus Williams,
-而我就要输大了  -这次又是什么事
- and I'm losing big time. - What, now?
我女儿  她来这里两天了
My daughter. She's here for two days
因为她被勒令停学了  更糟的是
because she got suspended, and worse,
我问她怎么回事  她对我撒谎
when I asked her what happened, she lied to me about it.
所以你来找我  因为你认为
So you're coming to me because you don't think
她现在听不进你和你老婆的话
she'll listen to you or your wife right now.
她是个聪明孩子  但现在
She's a smart kid, but right now
她只在乎做个酷女孩
all she cares about is being cool,
所以我需要像你一样的人向她展现
so I need someone like you to show her
-做个聪明人就很酷  -那你是在夸我酷咯
- that being smart is cool. - So you're saying I'm cool.
对于一个不听老爸话的
To a 15-year-old who won't listen
15岁女孩来说是的
to a word her father says, yes.
或许是因为她现在需要的
Well, maybe that's because she doesn't need
不是倾听  而是诉说
to listen right now, she needs to be heard.
因为我可以根据经验告诉你
Because I can tell you from experience,
做一个少女真的很难
being a teenage girl is pretty damn hard.
那就是说你答应了
Does that mean you'll do it?
我想是的
I guess it does.
别让我后悔找你帮忙
Just don't make me regret this.
亚历克斯  你要是现在还不知道的话
Alex, if you don't know by now,
我很擅长让别人后悔
making people regret things is kind of what I do.
那你和乔伊会相处得很好
Then you and Joy are gonna get along just fine.
谢谢你  萨曼莎
Thanks, Samantha.
-这是什么  -洗手液
- What is this? - Sanitizer.
我听说你用手做了件相当肮脏的事
I heard you had a particularly dirty case on your hands.
哈维告诉你了
Harvey told you.
你是说这是你经历的最困难的事吗
You mean that this was the hardest case you ever had?
诊所让你下不了台
That the client was really jerking you around?
-还有... -你说完了吗
- That... - Are you finished?
-说完了吗  -唐娜
- Are you finished? - Donna!
我只是作为朋友关心你
I'm just asking as a friend.
你成功屠龙了吗  你拍打土豆了吗
Did you slay the dragon? Did you bop the potato?
你冲上顶峰了吗
Did you wallop the badinger?
-"冲上顶峰"  -对  我现在创意不断
- "Wallop the badinger"? - Yeah, I was on a roll.
任何...不
Whatever--no...
路易  怎么了
Louis, what's wrong?
我只是在开玩笑
I was just joking around.
进展得不好吗
Did it not go okay?
-不是这件事  唐娜  -那是什么事
- It's not that, Donna. - Then what is it?
-万一我不能生育呢  -路易
- What if I can't have kids? - Louis...
这是我毕生的梦想
It is all I've ever wanted,
但我一直都没想到
but it has never once occurred to me
我有可能不能生育
that I might not be able to do it.
那你有没有意识到
Well, has it occurred to you that the reason
你没担心过这事的原因是不是在于
you were never worried is that there's no reason
-它没什么可担心的呢  -但希拉很担心
- to be worried? - Except Sheila is worried,
搞得现在我也开始担心了
and now it's in my head.
-唐娜  万一是我的问题呢  -路易
- Donna, what if it is me? - Louis, right now
现在我们都还不知道到底存不存在问题
we don't even know if there's a problem at all,
所以我建议你等真发现了问题再说吧
so I suggest you cross that bridge when you come to it.
如果真的有问题  然后你需要一个
And if you do, and you need someone
倾诉对象的时候  我还会在
to talk about it with, I'll be here.
谢谢你  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
你摸清马库斯的状况了吗
Hey. Did you get a hold of Marcus?
-摸清了  -到底什么情况
- I did. - Then what's going on?
-他不是又病了吧  -不  不是那么回事儿
- He's not sick again, is he? - No, nothing like that,
-但情况也不容乐观  -那是什么情况
- but it's still not good. - Then what is it?
他出轨了凯蒂
He cheated on Katie.
凯蒂发现了之后想和他离婚
She found out and now she wants a divorce.
哦  我的天啊
Oh, my God.
-你在逗我呢吧  -没有
- Are you kidding me? - No.
这还没完  他想让我去
And that's not all, he wants me to come up there
-当他的代表律师  -那你想怎么做
- and represent him. - So what are you gonna do?
你觉得我想怎么做
What do you think I'm gonna do?
-我得帮他  -好  听着  我得问你
- I’m gonna help him. - Okay, look, I have to ask--
你确定你要这么干吗
are you sure that you want to do this?
谢谢你的关心  唐娜  但那是我弟弟
I appreciate your concern, Donna, but it's my brother.
-我还能怎么做  -我的意思是
- What am I supposed to do? - All I'm saying
这有可能会让你惹上许多麻烦
is that this could bring up a lot of shit for you.
我不否认  但就像我说的
And I don't disagree, but like I said,
他是我弟弟
it's my brother.
-我还能怎么做  -好吧
- What am I supposed to do? - Okay.
但你走之前  发生了这么多事之后
But before you go, after what just happened
-我觉得你得告诉罗伯特  -我已经说了
- I think you should tell Robert. - I already did.
他什么反应
How did he take it?
这我得夸夸他了  他
I have to give him credit, he--
他完全没有犹豫
he didn't hesitate for a second.
他说  "家庭第一
He said, "Family comes first.
一直是第一  永远是第一"
Always does, always will."
你一定是乔伊吧
You must be Joy.
他们是这么叫我的
That's the name they gave me.
我是萨曼莎
I'm Samantha.
你爸爸今天一天都有会要开
Your dad's gonna be stuck in meetings all day,
所以他让我来看看你的情况
so he asked me to check in on you.
萨曼莎是吧
Samantha, is it?
他没让你来看看我的情况
He didn't ask you to check in on me.
他让你来监视我
He asked you to keep an eye on me
因为你是那个很酷的人
because you're the cool one.
他可能觉得你很酷
Well, you might be cool to him,
但我不觉得
but you're not cool to me.
好吧
Okay.
我明白这是什么情况了
I see what this is.
你告诉我你的故事  我就告诉你我的
I'll tell you mine if you tell me yours.
-什么故事  -我被停课的故事
- Your what? - My "Why I got suspended."
-你被停课了  -就一次
- You got suspended? - Just once.
但是是分别被三个学校各停了一次
But from three different schools.
这是个橄榄球场
That's the football field.
我用了工业漂白剂
I used industrial bleach.
那个鬼玩意儿几个月都弄不下来
That shit's not coming out for months.
哇  你的用词可真棒
Wow, that is some colorful language.
所以你干了些什么呢
So what'd you do?
最糟的那一次
The worst one?
我从学校停车场搞了辆车
I boosted a car from the school parking lot.
-你偷了别人的车  -不是别人的
- You stole somebody's car. - Not somebody's,
校长的
the principal's.
后来我发现这不是个好主意
Turns out that is not a good idea.
明白了
Got it.
不能偷校长的车
Don't steal the principal's car.
我不是说破坏规则不是好事
I'm not saying breaking the rules is a bad thing.
我是说你得知道哪些可以破坏
I'm saying you just need to know which ones to break.
我不觉得你应该告诉我这些
I don't think you're supposed to tell me that.
也许吧  但如果你要帮我的话
Maybe not, but if you're gonna help me
接下来几天里  你会知道我是怎么工作的
the next couple of days, you should know how I work.
-帮你  -是的
- Help you? - Yeah.
今天下午我有个取证
I've got a deposition this afternoon
但没什么可以制住对方
and nothing to force the other guy's hand.
你加入吗
You in?
-加入  -那么乔伊
- I'm in. - Well, then, Joy,
我们得去喝杯咖啡了
you and I are gonna need some coffee.
哈维  你来这里做什么
Harvey, what are you doing here?
我来是因为马库斯要我做他的律师
I'm here because Marcus asked me to represent him.
那你不该在我的律师不在场的情况下
Then you shouldn't be contacting me
-联系我  -是  我不应该
- without my lawyer. - No, I shouldn't.
但我不是作为律师来这里
But I'm not here as a lawyer.
我作为大哥来的
I'm here as your brother-in-law.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
我知道马库斯依然爱着你
It means I know Marcus still loves you, and...
我需要知道是否有办法
I need to know if there isn't still a way
在你们俩之间解决这个问题
that you guys can work this out.
虽然我也希望如此
And as much as I wish that could happen,
但为时已晚
it's too late for that.
马库斯告诉了我发生了什么
Look, Marcus told me what happened...
但你还是来试图
And you're still standing here
-为他辩解  -不  我不是
- trying to defend him. - No, I'm not.
当他告诉我时  相信我  我想一拳打上去
When he told me, believe me, I wanted to lay him out myself,
但我也知道
but I also know what it feels like
家庭破裂是什么感觉
to have your family ripped apart,
-我不想看这样的事发生  -你以为我想吗
- and I don't want to see that happen. - You think I do?
不  你也不想  但我告诉你
No, I don't, but I'm telling you,
一旦律师介入
the second lawyers get involved...
场面会很难看
it's gonna get messy.
已经很难看了  哈维
It's already messy, Harvey.
而且我的律师已经介入了
And my lawyer's already involved,
所以不管你是不是马库斯的律师
so be Marcus' lawyer or don't,
我不会再和你讲话了
but either way I can't talk to you anymore.
不  你坐这里
No, no, you sit here.
-为什么  -那边的两个
- Why? - Those two over there
是对方律师和他的客户
are opposing council and his client.
这和我坐哪里有什么关系呢
What does that have to do with where I sit?
和我坐在哪里有关系
It has to do with where I sit.
-我不明白  -听我解释
- I don't understand. - Let me explain.
我没这个混蛋的把柄  但我知道他在撒谎
I have nothing on this asshole, but I know he's lying.
所以我在一小时后要吓唬他
So I'm going to bluff him in an hour,
而这里是吓唬开始的地方
and this is where that bluff starts.
所以你就瞪他吗
So you're just gonna stare at him?
不  我要大笑
No, I'm also going to laugh
喝咖啡  向他证明
and drink my coffee and show him
我有多自信
how incredibly confident I am.
我明白了
I get it.
你在试图干扰他们的心智
You're trying to get in their heads.
-不是试图  正在做  -厉害
- Not trying, doing. - Awesome.
-我去买点喝的  -你请客吗
- I'll get us some drinks. - You're buying?
-我爸请客  -这样的话
- My dad's buying. - In that case,
我要一打百吉饼  七个甜甜圈
I will take a dozen bagels, seven donuts, and...
还有那边的高端浓缩咖啡机
one of those fancy espresso machines over there.
别告诉我  结果出来了
Don't tell me-- the results are in.
-是的  -然后呢
- They are. - And?
他们让我去亲自见医生
They want me to meet with the doctor in person.
-然后呢  -我想让你和我一起去
- And? - And I want you to come with me.
路易  我...
Louis, I--
我不想让你觉得我无情
I don't mean to sound insensitive,
但我真的觉得你应该自己去
but I really think that you should do this on your own.
唐娜  他们说"亲自"
Donna... they said "In person."
-肯定不好  -他们不是给每个人都这么说吗
- That can't be good. - But don't they do that for everyone?
也许是的
Maybe they do,
但我只是不想自己去
but I just don't want to be alone.
我理解  但我不是你应该问的
And I understand that, but I'm not the woman
那个女人
you should be asking.
-希拉  -这件事上她是你的同伴
- Sheila. - She's your partner in this.
我知道  但如果
I know that, but what if...
-如果什么  -唐娜  如果我是那个
- What if what? - Donna, if I'm the reason
我们要不了的原因  我希望由是我告诉她
we can't have kids, I wanna be the one to tell her.
而不是穿白大褂的某人
Not some guy in a lab coat.
而且如果你真的想让我和你去  我会的  但是...
And if you really want me to go with you, I will, but...
如果我是希拉  我不会想是
if I were Sheila, I wouldn't want
知道结果的第二个女人
to be the second woman in your life to find that out.
你说得对  唐娜
You're right, Donna.
别告诉我他们的咖啡卖完了
Don't tell me they ran out of coffee.
不  我有东西比咖啡更刺激
No, I got something better than coffee.
我不知道该怎么办  就点了录音键
I didn't know what to do, so I just hit "Record."
-有帮助吗  -自然是有的
- Does it help? - It sure as shit doesn't hurt.
这是不是意味着我们不用
Does that mean we don't have
干坐在这和他们卖笑
to sit here and smile at them?
你错了  这表明
No, it just means it's gonna be
将有一处好戏要上演了
a hell of a lot more fun.
哈维
Harvey.
你迟到了一个小时
You were supposed to be here an hour ago.
我得先去处理一些事
There was something I had to do first.
是哦  我知道你做的是什么
Yeah, I know what you had to do,
-我真希望你没去  -听着
- and I wish you hadn't done it. - Listen to me...
哈维  你说过要来这帮我
Harvey, you said you were gonna come up here and help me,
但没说要和凯蒂搞事情
not stir things up with Katie.
马库斯  你说要的是和平
Marcus, you said you wanted peace,
我也尽力了
so I tried to make peace.
你真的不是把事情搞得更糟吗
Yeah, well, what you did was make it worse.
-妈的  -那是几个意思
- Shit. - What does that mean,
"你被制裁了"
"You've been sanctioned"?
听着  那是个罚金
Look, it's a fine
因为我跳过了律师直接联系她
for contacting her without her lawyer.
-没什么大不了的  -不  我懂你得很
- It's nothing. - No, I know you,
这里头还有鬼
and there's something else.
要是我申请动议  那就好比掷硬币
If I file some kind of motion and it's a coin toss,
法官也许会向着他们那边
the judge probably rules in their favor.
-你特么在逗我吧  -马库斯  我很抱歉
- Are you ----ing kidding me? - Marcus, I am sorry.
是你让我来的
You asked me to come up here,
不管怎么说
and like it or not...
我也不容易  于是我就去和凯蒂联系
This is tough for me too, so I tried with Katie.
行了  哈维  我明白了
Okay, Harvey, I get it.
我也只能妄想有那百万分之一的机率
I just wish there was a chance in hell
这事儿还可能成
that it would've worked.
那我们现在怎么办
So what are we gonna do now?
我来告诉你我们怎么办
I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
你要一个和平协议
You want a peaceful settlement,
我们就搞定那个和平协议
we're gonna get you a peaceful settlement.
-利特先生  -你好
- Mr. Litt. - Yes.
-您请坐  -我的天咧
- Please, have a seat. - Oh, my God,
是比我想的还惨  我连一丢丢精子都没吧
it's worse than I thought. I have no sperm at all.
当然不是
Of course not.
实际上  我是来恭喜您
In fact, I'm happy to inform you
你的精子数完全正常
that your sperm count is perfectly fine.
我觉得你完全可以
I see no reason why you can't make
-让任何一个健康的女性怀孕  -太妙了
- any healthy woman pregnant. - Great, fantastic.
但有一件事
There is one thing, however.
-什么一件事  -我发现
- One thing. - I noticed
在咱们表格的生活方式一栏
on the lifestyle section of our form,
-你填了"泥浴"  -没毛病啊
- you put down "Mudding." - Yeah.
这是我放松的方式之一
Yes, it relaxes and soothes me.
你想想嘛  医生  不然我为什么
Come to think of it, doc, I think that's the reason
-精子数这么牛呢  -你得停止做这个
- why my count is so robust. - You'll have to give it up.
-怎么了又  -你的精子数是没问题
- What now? - Well, your count is fine,
但考虑到你夫人的年龄  如果你戒掉泥浴
but due to your partner's age-- if you give up mudding,
她怀孕的机率就会大幅上升
your chances of conceiving go up significantly.
-怎么大幅个法  -百分之八十
- Define significantly. - 80%.
亲娘姥爷哟  百分之八十
Holy shit, 80%?
-一定还有别的办法  -只有这个办法
- There's gotta be another way! - There isn't.
那我把蛋蛋留在外面不放进去行不行
What if I put everything in but my balls?
-我不  -得了
- I don't... - Scratch that,
-没有用  -利特先生
- defeats the purpose. - Mr. Litt...
我降低频率行不行
What if I cut down on my sessions?
我把次数减一半  怀孕机会上升40%
I cut it down in half, it improves our chances 40%.
不是这么个事儿啊
I'm afraid it doesn't work that way.
那你倒是说怎么办啊
Well, then what are you telling me?
我的意思是  如果你想要最大可能的
I'm telling you that if you want to have
让妻子怀上个孩子
the best chance at having a child,
在可预知的未来里  你都要戒掉泥浴
you'll give up mudding for the foreseeable future.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
这位姑娘何许人也  有何贵干
Who is she, and what's she doing here?
今天是"跟家长上班"日
It's "Go to work with your parent" Day.
这位敢情是您千金
She's your daughter?
差不多吧
Something like that.
当然啰  你要是太害怕她在这儿
But of course, if you're too afraid to have her here,
-她也可以回避  -她呆这儿对我无妨
- she doesn't have to be here. - Fine with me if she stays,
因为这将是
since this is gonna be
世界上最短的取证过程
the world's shortest deposition
因为你已经准备承认
Because you're ready to admit you infringed
侵犯我委托人的专利以制造假冒药品了吗
on my client's patent to create your generic knock-off?
因为是我的公司自己开发的新药
Because, my company developed that drug from scratch,
你的委托人根本没有我们造假的证据
and your client has no proof we didn't.
我们已经掌握了证据  只是不打算用
Actually, we do have proof, we're just not gonna use it.
你不打算用  是因为证据根本不存在
You're not gonna use it because it doesn't exist.
我不用
I'm not gonna use it
是因为我希望你在取证时当着我的面撒谎
because I'd like you to lie to my face in this deposition.
为什么
And why is that?
这样我在庭上揭发你的时候
So when I reveal what we know in open court,
你不仅会输官司  还会被控作伪证
you not only lose this case,you get charged with perjury.
你不会因此而坐牢吗
Can't you get sent to jail for that?
乔伊  也可能会坐牢
Why, yes, Joy, you can.
但更可能会先破产
But you'd probably go bankrupt, first,
打官司打到破产
trying to fight it.
你是在唬我们
You're bluffing.
你根本没有他的把柄
You don't have shit on him.
那我们只有一种方式能知道谁说的对了
I guess there's only one way to find out.
科尔曼先生  你到底有没有
So, Mr. Coleman, did you or did you not
侵犯我们的专利去做你的新药
rip off our patent to create your bullshit new drug?
在你回答之前
And before you answer,
先回想一下你来这里之前喝的那杯
I'd like you to think back to that decaf latte
低咖啡因拿铁
you were drinking before coming up here.
仔细回想一下在你桌子旁边
And, more specifically, to the person waiting in line
排队的人
by your table...
你当时正努力想把视线从我身上移开
while you were trying so hard not to look at me.
我明白她在干什么了
That's what she's doing here.
-你设计我们  -是你们设计了自己
- You set us up. - You set yourself up
你们去公共场合的时候
because you went to a public place
大声谈论这个案子  一个15岁的女孩
and discussed a case loud enough for a 15-year-old girl
碰巧在拍咖啡店里的场景
who just happened to be recording the coffee shop
把你们也拍进画面里了
to pick you up on tape.
现在  我再问你最后一次
Now, for the last time...
你的新药是怎么开发出来的
Where'd your new drug come from?
好吧
All right.
你想要多少钱
How much do you want?
抱歉让二位久等
Gentlemen, sorry to keep you waiting.
我和委托人刚刚在最后敲定一些问题
My client and I were just discussing a few last matters.
没关系
Not a problem.
既然你们也准备好了
Now that you're ready,
我提议先讨论财产分割问题
I suggest we start with division of property.
我们想先讨论最重要的问题
Actually, we'd like to start with the most important issue...
-孩子的抚养权  -是的
- Our kids. - Exactly.
因为我们想要单亲监护权
Because we're seeking sole custody.
什么  我们没讨论过这个
What? We--we didn't talk about that.
这与之前是否讨论过没有关系
And what was or wasn't previously discussed is irrelevant.
-胡--  -马库斯  让我来处理
- That's bull-- - Marcus, let me handle this.
他们不是真的想要单亲监护权
Because they don't really want sole custody,
他们只是挑个头
they just want to start on one end
希望我们能和她们对着干
because they're expecting us to start on the other.
但我们不是来吵架的
But we don't want a fight,
为什么我们不能折衷一下
so why don't we just all start in the middle?
我告诉你原因--因为没有商量的余地
I'll tell you why-- because we're not moving on this at all.
-什么  -凯蒂  别这样
- Excuse me? - Katie, don't do this.
你自作自受  马库斯
You did this to yourself, Marcus.
不  他没有  他是做了错事
No, he didn't. He may have screwed up,
但你没有理由带走孩子
but you don't have the grounds to take the kids.
-事实上  我们有理由  -胡扯
- Actually, we do. - Bullshit.
我不会让你玩那套
And I'm not gonna let you play games like you did
制裁措施的把戏
with those sanctions.
什么制裁措施
What sanctions?
你明知故问
You know what sanctions.
我找你谈话
The ones you had your lawyer slap me with
你就让律师找我麻烦
for coming to talk to you.
我从未允许任何这样的事
I didn't authorize anything like that.
不需要你允许
You didn't need to.
你告诉我他以不恰当的方式接触你以后
After you told me he approached you improperly...
你觉得这是个让法官产生偏见的好主意
You thought it was a good idea to use that to bias the judge.
我认为这是个好主意
I thought it would be a good idea
因为这能保护我委托人的利益
to protect my client's interests.
孩子不仅是你委托人的利益
Well, those kids aren't just your client's interests.
他们也是我弟弟的孩子
They're my brother's children--
那他本就应该
Well, then maybe he should have cared enough
把孩子的需要排在他的需要之前
to put their needs ahead of his own.
凯蒂  他可能不是个完美的丈夫
Katie, he may not have been a perfect husband,
但我不允许你说他不是个好爸爸
but I am not gonna let you say he's not a good father.
你凭什么知道他是什么样的爸爸
How would you know what kind of a father he is?
我告诉你  凭每次我看见他带孩子的时候
I'll tell you how. Every time I have seen them with him,
凭他每次和我谈起孩子们的时候
every time he has told me about them...
那他是怎么跟你说我们为什么分开的
And what about what he told you about why we're splitting up?
仅仅因为他跟别的人上过床
Just because he slept with someone else
并不代表他不是一个好父亲
doesn't mean he's not a good father.
跟别人上床
Slept with someone else?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
他没告诉你究竟发生了什么  对吧
He didn't tell you what happened, did he?
凯蒂
Katie...
马库斯  她说的是什么意思
Marcus, what's she talking about?
你知道吗  这事你们自己私下讨论
You know what? You can have that conversation on your own time,
我不允许你在连实情都不清楚的情况下
'cause I'm not gonna let you tell me this is all my fault
就把这一切都怪在我头上
when you don't even know the whole story.
我把话说清楚  孩子们的抚养权是我的
Let me be clear: I'm taking the kids
因为跟着我才是他们最好的出路
because that is what is best for them.
要是你有意见的话  哈维
And if you have a problem with that, Harvey,
你就去问一问坐你身边这人
you can take it up with the man sitting next to you,
因为我已经厌倦了为自己辩护
'cause I'm done defending myself.
凯蒂
Katie!
好了  你现在就告诉我
Okay, you tell me and you tell me now.
刚刚到底什么情况
What was that all about?
-我又去赌博了  -我真不敢相信
- I was gambling again. - I don't believe this...
我只赌了几个礼拜
It was just for a few weeks.
大概是一年以前的事
It was almost a year ago,
从那以后我一直在参加戒赌疗程
and I've been in a program ever since.
让我猜猜
Let me guess:
你当时没告诉凯蒂  就像没告诉我一样
you didn't tell Katie, just like you didn't tell me.
-我当时想告诉你的  -什么时候
- I was going to tell you. - When?
等法官把孩子判给凯蒂之后吗
After the judge took your kids?
因为他们这么做是对的  马库斯
Because they're right, Marcus.
他们有理由这么做
They do have the grounds to do that,
而且这理由是你提供的
and you gave it to them. -
哈维  你肯定还有别的办法
Harvey, there's gotta be something you can do here.
我不知道事实真相就没有
Not when I don't have all the facts!
我当时直截了当地问你发生了什么
I point-blank asked you what happened, and you said
你告诉我是因为一次外遇
it was because of an affair.
听着  我知道我早应该告诉你
Look, I know I should have told you,
但现在我说了
but I'm telling you now.
那你现在就告诉我
Well, then you tell me, right now,
其它一切我应该知道的事情
anything else I should know, and I mean anything.
当时海莉发现我在赌博
Haley caught me making a bet.
我告诉她我只是在玩游戏
and I told her that I was just playing a game,
这事可以是我们俩之间的小秘密
and that it could be our little secret.
-你开玩笑吧  -你要去哪
- Are you kidding me? - Hey, hey--where you going?
-回纽约  -请别走  你不能
- Back to New York. - No, please, you can't--
他们是我的孩子
These are my kids!
你让你的孩子们替你撒谎
Your kids that you asked to lie for you.
这让你跟妈妈毫无区别
which makes you no different than Mom was.
不  这么说不公平
No, that is not fair.
我的情况跟妈妈完全不同
What Mom did is nothing like this.
你让你的孩子们替你保守秘密
You asked your kids to keep your secrets.
-哪里不同了  -因为我就这么一次
- How is that different? - Because it was one time
而且海莉根本不知道我做的是错事
and Haley had no idea what I was doing was wrong.
你知道吗  关于你自己是什么样的人
You know what? Tell yourself whatever you want
你怎么想都行
about what kind of man you are.
你不仅是不称职的丈夫
You're not just a shitty husband;
还是个不称职的弟弟  我受够了
you're a shitty brother, and I'm done here.
这是为了什么
What's this for?
我知道你今天压力很大
Well, I know it was a stressful day,
我觉得你应该喝点
and I thought you deserved something
上面带小雨伞的饮品
with a little umbrella.
你都不知道压力有多大
You have no idea.
进行的如何
So how did it go?
-很顺利  -真的吗
- It was great. - Really?
他怎么说
What did he say?
他说我跟你造人应该没什么问题
He said I should have no issue getting you pregnant,
别的没了
and nothing else.
没说别的吗
Nothing else?
一句别的都没说
Absolutely not one thing else.
有意思  因为我听说你必须戒掉泥浴
That's funny, because I was told you have to give up mudding.
什么  你怎么知道
What? How'd you know that?
他们跟你会面完就给我打电话了
They called me right after they saw you.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
这是完全违背医患保密
This is a total violation of the doctor-patient...
废话少说  路易  表格上是你的签名
Cut the bullshit, Louis. You signed the form.
真正的问题是  你能做到吗
The question is, can you do this?
-我当然能做到  -你确定吗
- Of course I can do it. - Are you sure?
因为你都不敢告诉我这事
Because you couldn't even admit it to me.
我不想说是因为这事很难
I didn't wanna talk about it because it was a difficult thing,
但是我能搞定的
but I can handle it.
你知道对我来说拥有家庭最重要
You know nothing means more to me than having a family.
这我知道  路易  但我也知道你在想什么
I do know that, Louis, but I also know how your brain works,
你会尝试找出一个方法
and you're gonna try to figure out a way
说服自己  你能两者兼得
to convince yourself that you can have both.
我是成年人了  我告诉你
I am a grown man, and I am telling you,
如果医生让我放弃泥浴
if a doctor tells me I have to give up mudding,
-那我就放弃  -向我保证
- then I will give it up. - Promise me.
我保证
I promise.
妈  如果你是来谈马库斯的事的话
Mom, if you're here to talk about Marcus...
我当然是来和你谈马库斯的
Of course I'm here to talk about Marcus.
问题是  你到底让不让我进去
Question is, are you going to let me in or not?
那就请进  开始你的批判
Then go ahead and say your piece,
但我不会改变想法
but it's not gonna change my mind.
我不知道你会不会改主意
Well, I don't know if it will or it won't...
但我是来告诉你  你是对的
but I came to tell you you're right.
马库斯做了可怕的事
What Marcus did was horrible,
我明白你为何这么愤怒
and I understand you being furious,
但海莉才五年级
but Haley's in fifth grade.
她根本不知道赌博是什么
She barely knows what gambling is.
但她知道撒谎是什么
She knows what lying is.
她知道她的父亲让她那么做
She knows that her father asked her to do it.
马库斯对此感到非常抱歉
And Marcus feels terrible about that.
是啊  所有赌棍都这么说
Yeah, that's what all addicts say.
你弟弟从来没有你坚强
And your brother has never been as strong as you are,
-但那不代表  -这和是否坚强无关
- but that doesn't mean... - This isn't about strength.
没错  这有关原谅
No, it's about forgiveness.
我辜负了你们  但马库斯也原谅了我
And Marcus forgave me, even when I failed you both,
当你离开时他也原谅了你
and then he forgave you when you walked away.
你是说这是我欠他的吗
Are you saying I owe him?
我是说人非圣贤
I'm saying people make mistakes.
哈维  我知道你有多生气
Harvey, I know how angry you are...
但你不能让他失去孩子
but you can't let him lose his children.
因为从我的经验来看
Because I can tell you from personal experience
家长和孩子分开对双方来说都是最糟的
there is nothing worse for the parent or the child.
你想让我怎么回答
What am I supposed to say to that?
如果我说  我们知道的都是事实呢
How about if I say what we both know is true?
这全是我的错
This is all my fault.
是我给你们当了坏榜样
I modeled all of this behavior for both of you,
拜托  哈维
but please, Harvey,
别让他为我的错误付出代价
don't make him pay for my mistakes.
好  我会看着办的
Okay, I'll see what I can do.
但我要问你一些问题
But I'm gonna need to ask you some questions.
所以放松些
So make yourself comfortable,
因为我们还要在这里待一段时间
because we're gonna be here for a while.
我以为你再也不理我了
Thought you were done with me.
我是你的兄弟
I'm your brother.
我永远不会不理你
I'm never gonna be done with you.
-你和妈妈谈过了  -没错
- You talked to Mom. - I did.
基本上她就说这都是她的错
She basically said it was all her fault.
-那并不是  -我知道
- Well, it wasn't. - I know.
但如果我能原谅她  那我也应该能原谅你
But if I can forgive her, I should be able to forgive you too.
我找到了让你有共有监护权的方法
I figured out a way to get you shared custody.
但我要在协议中写
But I am putting in the agreement,
只要你再赌博  孩子就归她抚养
you ever gamble again, she gets the kids.
如果你不践行  我不管法律怎么规定
You don't live up to that, I don't care what the law says,
我会代表她确保这协议生效
I'll represent her to make sure that's what happens.
-好的  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
这说凯蒂无法胜任母亲的角色
This claims that Katie's an unfit mother.
你当时因工外出
You were traveling for work,
海莉在操场摔断了胳膊  凯蒂当时在哪里
and Haley broke her arm at the playground. Where was Katie?
她当时在开会  手机关机
She was in a meeting. Her phone was off.
所以你认为她今后会更上心
So you'd think she'd be more mindful in the future,
但两年后儿子在夏令营时迷了路
but when her son wandered off from camp two years later,
她在三个小时内都没给学校回电话
she didn't even bother calling them back for three hours.
她没有得到信息
She didn't get the message!
当你得到信息时  你飞速开车到那里
Well, when you got the message, you drove up there like a rocket
去找他
to go find him.
-哈维  你是在扭曲事实  -不
- Harvey, you're twisting the facts here. - No.
-我会争取到孩子  -但不能通过这个方式
- I am getting your children. - Not this way, you're not.
我知道这感觉很糟
I know this doesn't feel good,
但你说过  我们需要榴炮弹
but you said it: we need a howitzer.
-就是它了  -我不管
- This is it. - I don't care.
-马库斯  -凯蒂是一名好母亲
- Marcus... - Katie is a good mother.
她爱这些孩子
She loves those kids.
我不会让你这么说她
I'm not gonna let you say these things about her.
该死  马库斯  这是唯一的办法
Damn it, Marcus, there's no other way.
你是纽约最厉害的律师
You're the best goddamn closer in New York.
你不是一直这么说吗
Isn't that what you always say?
最厉害的律师会想出别的办法的
Well, the best goddamn closer would find another way.
老爸
Hey, Dad.
给你带了些油条
Got you some churros.
谢了  我本以为
Thanks, but I gotta say,
你会早早过来求着我回家
I thought you'd be here an hour ago begging to go home.
萨曼莎和我去了奥托玉米卷庆祝
Well, Samantha and I went to Otto's Tacos to celebrate.
-庆祝什么  -她在取证中大胜了一个男的
- Celebrate what? - Her destroying this dude in a deposition
全因为我给她的东西
all because of what I gave her.
她说我做的很棒
She said I did great.
"你给他的东西"是什么意思
What do you mean, "What you gave her"?
我无意听到
Well, I overheard this guy
这人跟他律师说他偷了药剂配方
telling his lawyer that they stole our drug formula,
-之后我就  -等等  你无意听到
- and then I just... - Wait a second, you overheard this?
不仅是无意听到了
I didn't just overhear it,
我还录音了
I recorded it.
之后在萨曼莎的取证中派上了用场
And then Samantha used it in a deposition.
她也不算真的用了
Well, she didn't really use it,
只是威胁要用  我觉得真的太酷了
she just threatened to use it, which I thought was pretty badass...
我想要你离那个女人远一点
I want you to stay the hell away from that woman.
-什么  -你听到了
- What? - You heard me.
一开始不是你想让我们
Wait, aren't you the one who wanted us to work together
-一起工作吗  -不是一起工作
- in the first place? - Not to work together,
是照看你  绝不是利用你
keep an eye on you, and definitely not use you.
她没利用我  是我自愿的
She didn't use me. I volunteered.
你不懂她做了什么  因为你才十五岁
You don't know what she did because you're 15 years old.
我是只有十五岁
Well, I may only be 15,
但我过来是想说  我不想跟你来上班
but I actually came in here to admit that I was wrong
这个想法是错的
for not wanting to come into work with you,
现在我非常期待明天
and that now I can't wait until tomorrow.
明天可不会像今天一样
Well, tomorrow's not gonna be like today,
因为你会远离那个女人
because you're gonna stay away from that woman.
-你不能逼我  -你最好相信我可以
- You can't make me do that! - You'd better believe I can.
你确实是个狠角色  不是吗
You really are a piece of work, aren't you?
不好意思  你不是应该过来
I'm sorry, shouldn't you be coming in here
感谢我照顾你女儿吗
to thank me for taking care of your daughter?
你以为这就是"照顾"的话
If you think what you did is what "Taking care of" means,
那我希望你永远别养花
I hope you never get a goddamn house plant,
-更别养小孩  -什么
- let alone a child. - Excuse me?
乔伊跟我说了你干的好事
Joy told me about the stunt you pulled,
你还告诉她她干得很棒
and how you told her she did a great job.
那你有没有告诉她录音别人的谈话
Well, did you also tell her it's illegal
-是违法的  -在公共场所录音
- to record someone else's conversation? - It is not illegal
可没有违法
to record sound in a public space.
不是那么回事  你心知肚明
That's not what happened and you know it.
无所谓  因为我没用那段录音
Well, it doesn't matter, because I didn't use the recording
因为没有必要
because I didn't need to.
我知道  因为如果你用了
Oh, I know that, because if you had,
我们现在面临的问题会很不一样
we'd have a whole other set of problems right now.
那会是什么问题
And what would those be?
因为我做的事是完全合法的
Because was I did was completely within the bounds of the law.
你根本不懂  对吧
You don't get it, do you?
我信任你  把女儿交给你
I trusted you with my daughter
她在学校遇到问题还撒谎
who's been getting in trouble and lying,
然后她又做这样的事
and then she does something like this.
你非但不告诉她这样做不对
And instead of you telling her it was wrong,
你还表扬她
you gave her a goddamn cookie.
我只是把她当成年人对待
What I did was treat her like an adult
让她看看这个世界的样子
and show her how the world works.
她不是成人  她可以和你我一样
Well, she's not an adult, and she can learn how the world works
慢慢认识这个世界  而不是在十五岁
when you and I did, and that's not 15.
有些人更早就明白了这些道理
Some of us learned a hell of a lot younger than that.
那你的成长过程一定很煎熬
Well, you must have had a shitty upbringing,
因为父母的任务不是教孩子
because a parent's job isn't to teach their kids
世界是什么样的
how the world is.
而是教他们世界应该是什么样的
A parent's job is to teach them how the world should be.
一开始是她的父亲让我跟她沟通的
Well, her parent asked me to get through to her
因为他自己做不到
in the first place because he couldn't do it himself.
这是...
Well...
我自己要克服的问题
that's on me to grapple with.
同时  你离我女儿远一点
In the meantime, stay the hell away from my daughter.
早上好  格蕾琴  你好吗...
Good morning, Gretchen. How are you this...
我很忙  路易  你得赶紧了
I'm busy, Louis, just like you'd better get.
所以我才过来了
Which is what I'm doing here.
等等  慢点  你在说什么
Wait, slow it down. What are you talking about?
-尼尔森的取证提前到明天了  -明天
- The Nielson depo got moved up to tomorrow. - Tomorrow?
琼·沃尔什要尽快出她要的季度报告
Yes, and Joan Walsh wants her quarterly update yesterday.
你办公室还有16件其它工作等着你呢
There are 16 other things waiting for you in your office.
你一点和希拉有个午餐约会  而我不知道
You got lunch with Sheila at 1:00, and I don't know what the hell...
停
Stop right there.
你得把一半的行程重新安排
You need to reschedule half of those things.
这就说到最后一件事了
That brings me to the last thing:
-我要去看牙医  -什么
- I gotta go to the dentist. - What?
格蕾琴  不  你不能就这么走了
Gretchen, no, you can't leave me like this.
你没听到我说的吗
Did you hear me?
我牙上有个科罗拉多那么大的洞
I got a hole in my tooth the size of Colorado.
另外  在你因为无法承受压力
And before you ask me to call Lipschitz
让我去找利普希茨医生之前
because you can't handle the pressure,
他下周才回城
he's out of town till next week.
祝你好运
Good luck.
泥浴愉快  路易
Good mudding, Louis.
-泥浴愉快  路易  -路易  泥浴愉快
- Good mudding, Louis. - Hey, Louis, good mudding.
-你也泥浴快乐  -祝你洗个顶级泥浴
- And good mudding to you. - Top of the mudding to you.
-泥浴愉快  -泥浴愉快
- Good mudding. - Good mudding.
泥浴愉快
Good mudding.
路易  泥浴愉快
Hey, Louis, good mudding.
泥浴  泥浴
Mudding...mudding...
今天要做什么
So what's on the agenda for today?
什么也没有
Nothing.
昨晚那通说教后  我以为今天见不到你了
After last night's lecture, I didn't think I'd be seeing you today.
我爸爸让我离你远点
Yeah, well, my dad told me to stay away from you,
但他什么都不明白
but he doesn't know anything.
-并非如此  -就是这样
- That's not true. - Yes, it is.
-他是个混蛋  -别这么说
- He's an asshole. - Don't say that.
为什么  这是事实
Why not? It's the truth.
我在你身上学到的比从任何成年人那里都多
I learned more from you than any adult ever,
所以他要是让我离你远点
so if he wants me to stay away from you,
-他就错了  -不
- he's wrong. - No...
乔伊  他没错
Joy, he's not.
我才是做错了那个人
I'm the one who was wrong.
关于我14岁偷的那辆车
That car I boosted when I was 14?
我没告诉你故事的另一半
I didn't tell you the other half of it.
我不止是被停课了  我被开除了
I didn't just get suspended; I got expelled.
天哪
Holy shit.
之后我面临一个选择  要么振作起来
And after that, I had a choice: either get my shit together
要么终生一事无成
or get nowhere in life.
等我上高中时  我得到了奖学金
So by the time I was a senior, I got a scholarship and...
这样我才能上得了大学
that's how I was able to go to college in the first place.
我用不着奖学金  我爸有钱
Well, I don't need a scholarship. My dad's rich.
要是你觉得你爸爸的用处就是这个
And if you think that's your father's value,
那说明你对他一无所知
you don't know anything.
不管你意识到没有
Whether you see it or not,
他都在关心你
he is looking out for you.
他才不关心我
He doesn't look out for me, okay?
-他就会对我指手画脚  -对你指手画脚
- He just tells me what to do. - Telling you what to do
就是关心你
is looking out for you.
作为一个需要有人指点时
As someone who didn't have anyone telling me
根本无人指点的人
what to do when I could have really used it...
你不明白你有多幸运
you have no idea how lucky you are.
不管你想不想听他的  我反正愿意听他的
So whether you want to listen to him or not, I do,
我们不会再一起工作了
and we're not working together anymore.
我没想到你会站他那边
I didn't think you'd take his side.
怎么说呢  你爸爸实际上很聪明
What can I say, turns out your father's pretty smart.
你有时也该听听他的话
You should listen to him sometime.
也许我会的
Maybe I will.
他这周说对了一件事
I mean, he was right about one thing this week...
是什么
Yeah? What's that?
你是个很酷的人
You are the cool one.
乔伊  我试图告诉你的是
Joy, what I'm trying to tell you...
也许你父亲才是那个酷的人
is I think maybe your dad is the cool one.
-介意我坐这里吗  -哈维  我告诉过你
- Mind if I sit? - Harvey, I told you,
没有我的律师在场时  我不会和你说话
I'm not talking to you without my lawyer.
我也努力告诉过你律师只会让事情变得丑恶
And I tried to tell you that lawyers only make things ugly.
这就是证据
Here's proof.
-这是什么  -这是你曾令孩子
- What is this? - It's a list of all the times
身处险境次数的清单
you put those kids at risk.
-这是胡说八道  -也许是  但这是
- This is bullshit. - Maybe, but it's the kind of bullshit
在法庭上有用的胡说八道
that works in court.
-你不会这么对我的  -你最好相信我会
- You wouldn't do this to me. - You'd better believe I would,
因为我关心孩子们
because I care about those kids,
并且我知道他们的人生需要你和马库斯
and I know they both need you and Marcus in their lives.
也许马库斯应该在干那些事之前
Well, then maybe Marcus should have thought about that
-在他做了他做的事之前  -他是该
- before he did what he did. - Yeah, he should have.
但他在反思了
But he's thinking about it now,
这也就是为什么尽管我很想用这个
which is why as much as I'd like to use this...
-他却不让  -什么
- He won't let me. - What?
我告诉了他只有这一个办法
I told him this was the only way.
他让我再找一个  因为他不愿意
He told me to find another one because he doesn't want to hurt you
让你受到更多伤害
any more than he already has.
凯蒂
Katie...
他爱你
he loves you...
不管你愿不愿意
and whether or not you're willing
再给你的婚姻一次机会
to give the marriage another chance...
都该再给他一个当父亲的机会
he deserves another chance as a father.
我真没想到会听到哈维·斯佩克特
I never thought I'd hear something like that
说出这种话
from Harvey Specter.
我学到的最宝贵的东西
Well, if there's one thing I've come around on,
就是家庭问题中
when it comes to family,
原谅比愤怒好太多
forgiveness is a hell of a lot better than anger.
我会考虑的
I'll think about it.
我别无他求
That's the most I can ask.
路易  三点多了
Louis, it's past 3:00.
两小时前我们就该在吃午餐了
We were supposed to go to lunch two hours ago.
我知道  今天工作一团忙乱
I know. Work was a shit-show
所以我给你带了这个
so I--I got you these
表达歉意
to say I'm sorry.
很漂亮
They're beautiful.
-我也有礼物给你  -什么礼物
- And I have a gift for you too. - Oh, yeah? What kind of gift?
最棒的礼物
The best kind.
你不用放弃泥浴
You don't have to give up mudding
因为我决定结扎输卵管
because I've decided to get my tubes tied.
什么  为什么
What? Why would you...?
因为显然泥浴对你来说
Because clearly mudding is more important to you
比要孩子更重要  所以我就想
than having a baby, so I thought,
不如让我们两个都轻松点
"Why not make it easier for both of us?"
-希拉  不是的  -你是打算告诉我
- Sheila, that's not... - You're gonna tell me
你指甲里的泥不是泥浴来的吗
that's not mud under your fingernails?
好吧  是的  -但只是最后一次了
All right, it is-- but it was just one last time.
我怎么信任你的保证
And how can I trust that that's true?
因为我说了
Because I just told you,
今天是工作太烦躁
work was ----ing crazy.
格雷琴给我找了一堆事
Gretchen was coming at me with 1,000 things.
-你不理解  -我理解
- You don't understand. - I do understand,
因为是我让她给你找事的
because I'm the one who asked her to come at you.
我理一下
So let me just get this straight:
你不信任我  所以就这么对我
you didn't trust me, so you did this to me.
不  我没有怎么对你
No, I didn't do anything to you.
你做出了一个承诺
You made me a promise.
你只要放弃一件事
All you had to do was let go of one thing,
-都没做到  -那是一件重要的事
- and you couldn't do it. - Well, it was a big thing,
如果不是最重要的的话
and I don't even know if it's the only thing.
那我理一下
Now, let me get this straight:
你不能把孩子的需求
you can't put the needs of our child...
-置于自己之上  -我不是这个意思
- above your own. - I'm not saying that.
那你什么意思
Okay, then what are you saying?
因为虽然我还不是母亲  但我知道
Because I may not be a mother yet, but I know
-那是父母的义务  -我也知道
- that's what parenthood means-- - So do I.
那要是他第一次生病时
Then what happens the first time he's sick
我们刚好要看芭蕾舞呢
when we have tickets to the ballet?
或者家长会刚好和
Or there's a deposition at the same time
取证撞时间了呢
as a parent-teacher conference?
-那不一样  -为什么
- Those are different. - How?
因为那时我是为他放弃那些事
Because I would be giving those things up for him,
而不是
not for...
为了我
For me.
不  你不是为了我放弃这些
No, you're not giving any of it up for me.
你是在为要一个孩子放弃这些
You're giving these things up to have a child.
你想知道我放弃了什么吗
Do you want to know what I'm giving up?
咖啡
Coffee...
酒精
and drinking...
芝士  和染发
and cheese, and my hair color--
更不要说从身体里硬挤出一个生命
not to mention the pain of pushing another human being
带来的痛苦
out of my body.
所以如果这么小的牺牲你都做不到
So if you're not ready to make this one little sacrifice,
那你就没准备好
then you're not ready...
要孩子
to have a child.
希拉  我很抱歉
Sheila, I'm sorry.
是我想错了  我不会再这样了
I wasn't thinking, and I won't--I won't--
我今天就把会员退掉
I'll just get rid of my membership today.
不  你不用退掉会员  路易
No, you don't have to give up your membership, Louis.
只要我怀孕前你戒掉就行
You just have to stop till we get pregnant.
你不懂吗
Don't you see?
如果不退
If I keep it...
我就会被诱惑
I'll be tempted.
希拉  拥有一个家庭对于我
Sheila, having a family is far more important to me
远比泥浴重要
than going mudding.
好
Okay, good.
我猜猜  你把事情解决了
Let me guess: you fixed everything,
现在给我来电话告诉罗伯特
and you're calling me to tell Robert
你明早就回来
that you'll be back in the morning.
好吧  读心术专家
Okay, mind reader.
我该怎么回答
What do I have to say to that?
不知道  哈维  但是
I don't know, Harvey, but...
我很高兴你去了
I'm glad you went.
说实话
To tell you the truth...
那是我做过的最不容易的事
it was one of the hardest things I've ever had to do.
我发誓我的心都少了一块  唐娜
I swear it took a piece of me, Donna.
你可以这么想
Well, you could look at it that way,
或者你可以认为
or you could look at it like you chose
是你主动放弃了一块
to give a piece of yourself.
厉害
That's pretty good.
你应该当个哲学家
You should be a philosopher.
谁说我不是了
And who's to say I'm not?
请允许我失陪  我有一块东西
Oh, now, if you'll excuse me, I need to give a piece
要给另一个人
of something to someone else.
谢谢  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
唐娜  无意冒犯  但是咖啡
Donna, no offense, but a cup of coffee
是我现在最不需要的东西
is the last thing I need right now.
其他的不说  戒咖啡因我就够头疼了
Among other things, I'm trying to give up caffeine.
我知道  路易
I know that, Louis...
而且这不是咖啡
and that's not coffee.
天哪  不会是...
Oh, my God, don't tell me it's...
富铁秘鲁泥
Iron-rich Peruvian ground silt heated
加热到华氏102.68度
to the recommended temperature of 102.68 degrees Fahrenheit.
希拉跟你说我退了会员  对吧
Sheila told you I sold my membership, didn't she?
是的  我得说
She did, and I have to say
我觉得这是我知道的最浪漫的事
I think that's the most romantic thing I've ever heard.
谢谢  唐娜
Thanks, Donna.
谢谢
And thanks for this.
还有一件事
One more thing.
我有种感觉你可能很快
Something tells me that you're gonna need this
就需要它喝咖啡了
for coffee sooner than you think.
世界最棒的父亲
晚安  路易
Good night, Louis.
有时间吗
You have a minute?
-看什么事了  -我不该说那些
- Depends on what it's for. - I shouldn't have said
关于你的恶劣的话
what I said about your upbringing.
-还有呢  -不管你跟乔伊说了什么
- And? - Whatever you said to Joy...
-我都很感激  -我和高兴
- I appreciate it. - I'm glad.
你跟她讲的你家的故事是真的吗
Is it true, what you told her about family?
我不想跟你讲我的童年  亚历克斯
I don't want to talk to you about my childhood, Alex.
真实的是  你是个好父亲
What is true is you're a good father.
我过分了  我很抱歉
I overstepped my bounds. I'm sorry.
-糟糕  -怎么了
- Aww, shit... - What?
我跟你说了  我想让乔伊做正确的事
I told you I'm trying to teach Joy to do the right thing,
但我在你的事上没有做到
but I haven't done right by you.
你跟我说赞恩保证你的名字会上墙
You told me Zane promised your name would be next on that wall,
但我没告诉你
but I didn't tell you
哈维也对我做了这个承诺
that Harvey promised me the exact same thing.
那么
Well...
现在你说了  你要放弃吗
now that you have, you wanna give it up?
不
No.
-你呢  -不要
- You? - No.
-想分享吗  -不
- You wanna share it together? - No.
我也是
Me either.
看来只有一句话好说了
I guess there's only one thing left to say.
我想是的
I guess there is.
-到时候  -看谁是更厉害的女人了
- When the time comes... - May the best woman win.